(新墨西哥州 普恩特 安蒂卡)
Wait for it.
等等
- Can I turn on the radio? - No.
- 我能开收音机吗? - 不行
Jane, you can't keep doing this.
珍妮,你不该老是搞这玩意儿的
The last 17 occurrences have been predictable to the second.
这最后第17个气旋很快就可侦测完了
Jane, you're an astrophysicist, not some storm chaser.
珍妮,你是天体学家,不是风暴追逐者
I'm telling you, there's a connection
我跟你说,有某种关连
between these atmospheric disturbances and my research.
在那里的几个气旋和我的研究之间
Erik, I wouldn't have asked you to fly out here
艾瑞克,我又不会要求你飞行到那上面去
if I wasn't absolutely sure.
这我敢保证
Jane?
珍妮?
I think you want to see this.
我想你该来看看这个
What is that?
那是什么?
I thought you said it was a subtle aurora!
我以为你说的只是极光而已!
Go!
快走!
- Get closer. - Right. Good one.
- 靠近一点 - 这回是好现象
Go!
快走!
What are you doing?
你在做什么啊?
I am not dying for six college credits!
我可不会为了几个学分去送命啊!
I think that was legally your fault.
我肯定都是你的错
Get the first aid Kit.
快去拿急救箱
Do me a favor and don't be dead.
拜托你千万别死啊
Please.
求你了
Where did he come from?
他从哪来的啊?
(挪威  滕斯贝格城  西元965年)
Once,
一旦
mankind accepted a simple truth,
人们开始信仰一个简单的事实
that they were not alone in this universe.
在这宇宙中我们就不孤单
Some worlds man believed to be home to their gods.
在某些世界里,人们学会景仰天神
Others, they knew to fear.
但有时候得学会去畏惧
From a realm of cold and darkness came the Frost Giants,
当黑暗来临,大地冻结,一个"寒冰巨人之王"出现
threatening to plunge the mortal world into a new ice age.
威胁要将人类别世界变成新的冰河时期
But humanity would not face this threat alone.
但人类别并非单独对抗这个威胁
Our armies drove the Frost Giants
我们的大军抵挡着寒冰巨人大军
back into the heart of their own world.
将他们击退回他们的国度
The cost was great.
但也付出极大的代价
In the end,
最后
their king fell.
寒冰王战败了
And the source of their power was taken from them.
而且,我们带走了他们"神器"
With the last great war ended,
当大战终告结束
we withdrew from the other worlds and returned home
我们也开始回家,回到我们的世界
to the Realm Eternal,
那永恒国度
Asgard
阿斯嘉特(神的领域)
Here we remain as a beacon of hope,
在此,我们保持着希望的光芒
shining out across the stars.
将希望的光芒透过星辰绽放
And though we have fallen into man's myths and legends,
虽然人类别将我们当作神话或传说
it was Asgard
但阿斯嘉特
and its warriors
及其战士们
that brought peace
把和平带给
to the universe.
宇宙
But the day will come
终究有一天
when one of you
你们其中一位
will have to defend that peace.
将必须维持这个和平
Do the Frost Giants still live?
寒冰巨人还活着吗?
When I'm king,
有天我当国王时
I'll hunt the monsters down and slay them all!
我将追杀此怪物并痛宰他们!
Just as you did, Father.
就像跟随您的脚步一样,父亲
A wise king
有智慧的国王
never seeks out war.
不该求战的
But he must always be ready for it.
但是你们应该做好准备随时应战
- I'm ready, Father. - So am I.
- 我准备好了,父亲 - 我也是
Only one of you can ascend to the throne.
你俩只能有一人戴上皇冠
But both of you were born to be kings.
但你们都生来就是要当王的
Oh, please.
拜托喔.
Thor Odinson,
托尔·奥丁之子
my heir,
我的继任者
my firstborn.
我的长子
So long entrusted with the mighty hammer Mjolnir,
掌握着雷神之锤
forged in the heart of a dying star,
由垂死之星锻造而成的
its power has no equal,
它的威力无可比拟
as a weapon to destroy
不仅是毁灭的武器
or as a tool to build.
更是创造的工具
'Tis a fit companion for a king.
他值得拥有一个国王的
I have defended Asgard
我们捍卫着阿斯嘉特
and the lives of the innocent across the Nine Realms
及其穿越九大国度的无辜生灵们
from the time of the great beginning.
就从此时此刻的伟大起点
Though the day has come...
尽管这一天来...
Do you swear to guard the Nine Realms?
你发誓将保卫九大国度吗?
I swear.
我发誓
And do you swear to preserve the peace?
并发誓保持和平吗?
I swear.
我发誓
Do you swear
你发誓
to cast aside all selfish ambition
将抛开自私的野心
and to pledge yourself only to the good of the Realms?
只专一的奉献自己保卫神之国度?
I swear!
我发誓!
Then, on this day,
值此今日
I, Odin Allfather,
我,奥丁,身为人父
proclaim you...
宣告你成为...
The Frost Giants!
"寒冰巨人"来袭!
The Jotuns must pay for what they've done!
巨人该为所做的付出代价!
They have paid, with their lives.
他们已经付出生命代价了
The Destroyer did its work,
他们没得逞
the Casket is safe, and all is well.
且"神器"也安好
All is Well?
安好?
They broke into the weapons vault!
他们闯入了武器库!
If the Frost Giants had stolen even one of these relics...
万一寒冰巨人抢走这些神器的之一...
- They didn't. - Well, I want to know why!
- 他们没成功 - 我要知道为什么!
I have a truce with Laufey, King of the Jotuns.
我跟劳菲有个和平协议,寒冰巨人王
He just broke your truce! They know you are vulnerable!
他刚违反和平协议!他们知道你变得脆弱了!
What action would you take?
换做你会怎做呢?
March into Jotunheim as you once did. Teach them a lesson.
我要去卓顿海姆,就想您以前一样,给它们个教训
Break their spirits
打击它们士气
so they'll never dare try to cross our borders again.
让他们不敢再越雷池一步
You're thinking only as a warrior.
你只是一个战士的想法
This was an act of war!
这就是战争的做法啊!
It was the act of but a few, doomed to fail.
这样的做法只是注定失败
Look how far they got!
你看他们侵入到多深的内部了!
We will find the breach in our defenses and it will be sealed.
我们会找出安检漏洞并加强防范
As King of Asgard....
身为阿斯加特的国王...
But you're not king!
但你还不是国王!
Not yer.
还不是
It's unwise to be in my company right now, Brother.
此时来找我谈是不智的,兄弟
This was to be my day of triumph.
这该是我立功的时候了
It'll come.
会到的
In time.
适时的
What's this?
怎么回事啊?
If it's any consolation, I think you're right.
我不是安慰你,我认为你是对的
About the Frost Giants, about Laufey, about everything.
有关寒冰巨人所作所为之类别
If they found a way to penetrate Asgard's defenses once,
如果它们能找到安检漏洞侵入阿斯加特
who's to say they won't try again?
难保他们下回不会再做
- Next time with an army. - Exactly.
- 而且带大军来袭 - 没错
There's nothing you can do without defying Father.
但你还是不能做出违背父亲的事来
No, no, no. I know that look.
不,我知道你要做什么
That's the only way to ensure the safety of our borders.
唯一要做的是确保边界安全
Thor, it's madness.
托尔,太疯狂了
Madness? What sort of madness?
疯狂?什么叫疯狂?
We're going to Jotunheim.
我们将前往"乔登海姆"
What?
什么?
This isn't like a journey to Earth
那可不像去地球旅行
where you summon a little lightning and thunder,
随意带着闪电和雷鸣
and the mortals worship you as a god.
让人类别像神般尊崇你而已
This is Jotunheim.
那可是:"乔登海姆"啊
My father fought his way into Jotunheim,
我父亲曾在"乔登海姆"作战过
defeated their armies and took their Casket.
他曾击败过大军,让敌方大败
We would just be looking for answers.
我只想去找答案
It is forbidden!
那是禁忌之地!
My friends, have you forgotten all that we have done together?
朋友们,你们忘了我们曾一起做过的事吗?
Fandral, Hogun.
范达尔,格里姆
Who led you into the most glorious of battles?
是谁让你们参与了光荣的战役?
You did.
是你
And Volstagg, to delicacies so succulent,
佛尔斯提格,我优秀的战将
you thought you'd died and gone to Valhalla?
是谁让你免于死在瓦哈拉的战役?
You did.
是你
Yes!
是的!
And who proved wrong all who scoffed at the idea
那又是谁向各位证明了
that a young maiden could be one of the fiercest warriors
既使是一个少女也能成为一代战将
this realm has ever known?
在国度里人尽皆知?
I did.
当然是我
True, but I supported you, Sif.
是的,但我支持你的说法,希芙
My friends,
朋友们
we're going to Jotunheim.
我们将前往:"乔登海姆"
You leave this to me.
让我来说
- Good Heimdall... - You're not dressed warmly enough.
- 你好海姆达尔... - 你们不仅让我感到警戒而已
I'm sorry?
什么?
Do you think that you can deceive me?
你们以为能蒙骗我吗?
- You must be mistaken... - Enough!
- 一定是误会了 - 够了!
Heimdall, may we pass?
海姆达尔,让我们走?
Never has an enemy slipped my watch until this day.
直到昨天以前我不曾让任何敌人进得来
I wish to know how that happened.
我很想搞懂是为什么
Then tell no one where we have gone until we've returned.
直到我们回来前别告诉任何人就好
Understand?
同意吗?
What happened? Silver tongue turn to lead?
怎么啦?舌头打结了啊?
Be warned.
我们曾发誓
I will honor my sworn oath to protect this realm as its Gatekeeper.
身为守护者,必将遵守誓言护卫国度
If your return threatens the safety of Asgard,
如果你们回来时阿斯嘉特的安全受到威胁
Bifrost will remain closed to you
彩虹桥将保持关闭
and you'll be left to die in the cold waste of Jotunheim.
而你们将会永远被遗忘在"乔登海姆"
Couldn't you just leave the bridge open for us?
你就不能直接开启门给我们吗?
To leave the bridge open
如果随意开启彩虹桥
would unleash the full power of the Bifrost
将会释放所有的力量
and destroy Jotunheim with you upon it.
同时摧毁"乔登海姆"以及你们
I have no plans to die today.
我今天没送死的打算
None do.
希望是的
We shouldn't be here.
早知道不该来的
Let's move.
我们走
Where are they?
他们人呢?
Hiding,
藏起来了
as cowards always do.
一向都是胆小鬼
You've come a long way to die, Asgardians.
你们大老远来就想送死,阿斯嘉特人
I am Thor Odinson!
我是托尔奥丁之子!
We know who you are.
我们知道你是谁
How did your people get into Asgarol?
你们是怎样渗透进来我们阿斯加特的?
The House of Odin is full of traitors.
你们有许多背叛者
Do not dishonor my father's name with your lies!
不准你用谎言污蔑我父之名!
Your father is a murderer and a thief!
你父亲是个杀人犯跟小偷!
And why have you come here? To make peace?
所以你想来这里?寻求和平?
You long for battle. You crave it.
你距离上回大战太久了,而你想参与
You're nothing but a boy
好让你这小子
trying to prove himself a man.
证明你是个大男子汉
Well, this "boy" has grown tired of your mockery.
"这小子"厌烦听你再继续胡说
Thor, stop and think.
托尔,暂停并思考
Look around you, we're outnumbered.
看看四周我们人数不多
Know your place, Brother.
弟弟.搞清楚你的地位
You know not what your actions would unleash.
你们不懂我将释放出的能量有多危险
I do.
我知道
Go now, while I still allow it.
离开吧,否则我不手下留情的
We will accept your most gracious offer.
我们接受您提出的协议
Come on, Brother.
走吧,兄弟
Run back home, little princess.
滚回家吧,小公主
Damn.
糟了
Next?
下一位?
At least make it a challenge for me!
少说给我个挑战吧
That's more like it.
还不错嘛
Don't let them touch you!
别让它们碰触到你!
Thor!
托尔!
- We must go! - Then go!
- 该离开了! - 哪走啊!
Run!
跑!
Thor!
托尔!
Heimdall!
海姆达尔!
Open the bridge!
打开彩虹桥!
Father! We'll finish them together!
父王!我们一起消灭他们!
Silence!
安静!
Allfather.
老爹啊
You look weary.
你看来累了
Laufey,
劳菲
end this now.
到此为止了
Your boy sought this out.
是你儿子引起的事端
You're right.
没错
And these are the actions of a boy, treat them as such.
确实是我儿子搞的小孩子把戏
You and I can end this here and now, before there's further bloodshed.
你大可以在此平息此事,避免引起日后的屠杀
We are beyond diplomacy now, Allfather.
此事已经不再是和平协议的一项了
He'll get what he came for.
他将遭受随之而来的
War
战争
and death.
与死亡
So be it.
那就这样吧
Why did you bring us back?
为何要带我们回来?
Do you realize what you've done?
你知道你闯了什么大祸了吗?
- What you've started? - I was protecting my home.
- 你在干什么? - 你我是在保卫家园
You cannot even protect your friends!
你连朋友都差点保护不了!
How can you hope to protect a kingdom?
现在你还想保卫家园?
Get him to the healing room! Now!
带伤者去医疗大厅!快去!
There won't be a kingdom to protect if you're afraid to act.
害怕有所作为只怕到时都没家园可保护了
The Jotuns must learn to fear me, just as they once feared you.
寒冰王要学会畏惧我,正如畏惧你一般
That's pride and vanity talking, not leadership.
只会大谈有多自豪或多有自尊没用
You've forgotten everything I taught you about a warrior's patience.
我教你的所有事情还包括:战士精神
While you wait and be patient, the Nine Realms laugh at us.
你再拖延应战时机,那其他九大国度都会嘲笑我们
The old ways are done.
他们老生常谈的说:
You'd stand giving speeches while Asgard falls.
你越不出声,到时神之国度将毁
You are a vain, greedy, cruel boy!
你真是个自负的小子,贪婪又残酷!
And you are an old man and a fool!
而你是个老头跟笨蛋!
Yes.
是
I was a fool
我是笨蛋
to think you were ready.
笨到相信你真的准备好了
Father...
父王...
Thor Odinson,
托尔·奥丁之子
you have betrayed the express command of your king.
你已经违背了国王命令
Through your arrogance and stupidity,
起因你的傲慢以及愚蠢
you've opened these peaceful realms and innocent lives
你扰乱了和平之地,也害了无辜百姓
to the horror and desolation of war!
带来了恐惧与战争!
You are unworthy of these realms!
你配不上这神之国度!
You're unworthy of your title!
你配不上你的头衔!
You're unworthy
你不值得
of the loved ones you have betrayed.
为人所爱戴,你背叛了
I now take from you your power!
我将取回你的神力!
In the name of my father
以我众神之父
and his father before,
其上之父之名
I, Odin Allfather, cast you out!
我,奥丁国度之父,我诅咒你!
Whosoever holds this hammer, if he be worthy,
无论雷神之锤落入谁手中,只要有资格的人
shall possess the power of Thor.
都可以拥有雷神之力
I think that was legally your fault.
我肯定都是你的错
Get the first aid Kit.
快去拿急救箱
Do me a favor and don't be dead.
拜托啊,千万别死啊你
Whoa. Does he need CPR? Because I totally know CPR.
他好像需要CPR?,但我不会做CPR
Where did he come from?
他从哪来的啊?
You all right?
你还好吧?
Hammer?
锤子?
锤子(音同酒醉)呢?
Yeah, we can tell you're hammered. It's pretty obvious.
是啊,你肯定是酒醉了,很明显
Oh, my God. Erik, look at this!
艾瑞克,快来看
We have to move quickly before this all changes.
我们得在改变前快点拍下照片
Jane, we have to take him to the hospital.
珍妮,得快带他去医院
- Father! - He's fine, look at him.
- 父王! - 你看他还好好的
Heimdall! I know you can hear me! Open the Bifrost!
海姆达尔!我知道你听得见!快开启彩虹桥!
Hospital. You go, I'll stay.
你带他去医院,我留下
You. What realm is this?
你,这是哪个国度?
Alfheim? Nornheim?
爱尔菲海姆?,多伦海姆?
New Mexico?
新墨西哥州啊
You dare threaten me, Thor, with so puny a weapon?
你敢威胁我,托尔,带着如此不堪的武器?
What? He was freaking me out!
怎样?我被吓到了啊!
Next time you decide to taser somebody,
下回你打算电击某个人之前
make sure he's already in the car, okay?
请先确定他人已在车上,好吗?
Jane! Come on.
珍妮!上车
Name?
姓名?
He said it was Thor?
他说他叫做托尔?
T-H-O-R.
"T-H-O-R"
- And your relationship to him? - I've never met him before.
- 你们跟他是什么关系? - 我从未见过他
Until she hit him with a car.
直到他被车撞了
I grazed him, but she tasered him.
我发现了他,然后她电击了他
Yes, I did.
是的,我干的
Hi.
嗨
Just taking a little blood.
先抽点血验验
How dare you attack the son of Odin?
好大胆,我可是奥丁之子啊
I need some help!
我需要帮忙!
Call security!
快叫保安!
Security to ER 3, stat!
保安快到3号病房!
You're no match for the Mighty...
你们都不是我的对手...
You don't think this was just a magnetic storm, do you?
你不认为这只是太阳风暴是吧?
Look, the lensing around these edges
你看,景象的边缘
is characteristic of an Einstein-Rosen Bridge.
就像"爱因斯坦·罗森桥"
A what?
什么东西?
- I thought you were a science major? - Political science.
- 我以为你还是天体研究者? - 政治系的
She was the only applicant.
她只是工读生而已
An Einstein-Rosen Bridge is a theoretical connection
"爱因斯坦·罗森桥"是在理论上连接
between two different points of space-time.
两个不同时空的宇宙点
It's a wormhole.
就是虫洞
- Erik, look. What do you see? - Stars.
- 艾瑞克,你看见什么了? - 星星啊
Yeah, but not our stars.
是的,但不是只有星体排列的图罢了
See, this is the star alignment for our quadrant this time of year,
这不只是今年的星象排列如此
and unless Ursa Minor decided to take a day off,
且这不是说星象可以乱改变的
these are someone else's constellations.
这是来自不同星系的影像
Hey! Check this out.
嘿,过来看看
No, it can't be.
不,这不可能
I think I left something at the hospital.
我们好像忘了什么东西在医院了
It's not possible!
这不可能!
He was on drugs or something. He just went nuts.
他是嗑药什么的了,他就是发疯了
Oh, my God.
天啊
I just lost my most important piece of evidence.
我刚搞丢了一个重要的确实证据
Typical.
实证
- So now what? - We find him.
- 现在呢? - 找到他
Did you see what he did in there?
你看到那里刚发生的事了吧?
I'm not sure finding him is the best idea.
我觉得找到他不是个好主意
Well, our data can't tell us what it was like to be inside that event,
我们的资料能让我们了解的有限
and he can. So, we're gonna find him.
而他却能告诉我们真相,所以要找到他
Okay.
好吧
So we're gonna look all over New Mexico, right?
就算翻遍新墨西哥州,对吗?
Exactly.
没错
What?
做什么啊?
I'm so sorry. I swear I'm not doing this on purpose.
抱歉,我不是故意的啦
I got it, I got it.
我来
Come on, kick it in now!
加油!用力!
Did it Work?
有用吗?
Sir, we found it.
长官,我找到了
You know, for a crazy homeless person, he's pretty cut.
以一个游民来说,他算满帅的
Hey, sorry I tased you!
抱歉我电击了你
Excuse me, excuse me!
抱歉,抱歉!
What is this?
这是什么啊?
My ex.
前男友的名牌
Good with patients and bad with relationships.
那段关系也维持的不怎么样
They're the only clothes I had that would fit you.
这是我能找到适合你的唯一衣服了
They will suffice.
衣服可以穿
You're welcome.
不客气
This mortal form has grown weak.
凡人的样子让我变虚弱
I need sustenance.
我需要进食
We should never have let him go.
我们不该放逐他的
There was no stopping him.
我阻止不了的
Well, at least he's only banished, not dead.
至少还好是放逐,不是处死
Which is what we'd all be
我们早都死了
if that guard hadn't told Odin where we'd gone.
如果守护者没有告诉奥丁我们去哪儿了
How did the guard even know?
守护者怎知我们上哪去?
I told him.
我说的
What?
什么?
I told him to go to Odin after we'd left.
我要他在我们离开后通报父王
He should be flogged for taking so long.
我担心这趟行程拖太久
We should never have reached Jotunheim.
怕在"乔登海姆"待太久
You told the guard?
是你告密的?
I saved our lives.
我可救了大家啊
And Thor's.
也救了托尔
I had no idea Father would banish him for what he did.
但我并不知道父王将如何逞罚他
Loki.
洛基
You must go to the Allfather and convince him to change his mind.
你必须向父王求情,要求他改变心意
And if I do, then what?
那又能如何呢?
I love Thor more dearly than any of you, but you know what he is.
我比你们更爱托尔,但你们了解他
He's arrogant. He's reckless. He's dangerous.
他很自傲,他很蛮干,他很危险
You saw how he was today.
你们亲眼目睹的
Is that what Asgard needs from its king?
神之国度能接受这种国王吗?
He may speak of the good of Asgard,
他能声称自己很爱"阿斯嘉特"国度
but he's always been jealous of Thor.
但他总是一直在忌妒托尔
We should be grateful to him, he saved our lives.
至少我们该感谢他救了咱们
Laufey said
劳菲说
there were traitors in the House of Odin.
在奥丁王宫里有反叛者
A master of magic could bring three Jotuns into Asgard.
魔法也可以至少送进3人进入"阿斯嘉特"
Loki's always been one for mischief,
洛基也许有时比较调皮点
but you're talking about something else entirely.
但你们这样指控可是很严重的
Stop!
住手!
Am I cursed?
我被诅咒了吗?
No.
没有
What am I?
那我算什么?
You're my son.
你是我儿子
What more than that?
那又怎样呢?
The Casket wasn't the only thing you took from Jotunheim that day,
这个箱子不是唯一一个你从"乔登海姆"带回的东西
was it?
是吧?
No.
不是的
In the aftermath of the battle,
当大战后
I went into the temple and I found a baby.
我到神庙里发现了一个婴儿
Small for a giant's offspring.
娇小,也似乎很脆弱
Abandoned, suffering, left to die.
被遗落在那里似乎在等死
Laufey's son.
"寒冰王"劳菲之子
劳菲之子
Yes.
是的
Why?
为什么?
You were knee-deep in Jotun blood, why would you take me?
你有你自己的血脉继承者,为何还要养我?
You were an innocent child.
你只是无辜的小孩罢了
No. You took me for a purpose. What was it?
不,你肯应有原因要带走我的,是什么?
Tell me!
告诉我!
I thought we could unite our kingdoms one day.
我认为我们可以在某日结盟
Bring about an alliance, bring about permanent peace.
进而追求永和的和平
Through you.
透过你
What?
什么?
But those plans no longer matter.
但计划赶不上变化了
So I am no more than another stolen relic,
所以我变成无用之物
locked up here until you might have use of me.
被抢走还软禁在此好让你改天有机会利用
Why do you twist my words?
你别曲解我的意思?
You could have told me what I was from the beginning,
你大可告诉我,我是何身世的人
why didn't you?
你为何不说?
You're my son.
你是我儿子
I wanted only to protect you from the truth.
我只想着实的保护着你
Because I'm the monster
我就是所谓
parents tell their children about at night?
从小听到大恶魔?
- No, no. - You know, it all makes sense now!
- 不,不 - 就不肯告诉我实情!
Why you favored Thor all these years!
为何这些年你偏爱托尔!
Because no matter how much you claim to love me,
因为不管你如何口口声声说爱我
you could never have a Frost Giant sitting on the throne of Asgard!
但也不可能让寒冰王之子坐拥王位的!
Guards!
卫兵!
Guards, please, help!
卫兵,快帮忙!
How'd you get inside that cloud?
你是怎么跑进那云团里的啊?
Also, how could you eat an entire box of Pop-Tarts
还有,你怎么能在吃掉一整箱的果酱馅饼后
and still be this hungry?
还是这么饥饿啊?
- This drink, I like it. - I know. It's great, right?
- 这饮料,我喜欢 - 很不错吧?
Another!
再来一杯!
Sorry, Izzy. Little accident.
抱歉,有点小意外
- What was that? - It was delicious. I want another.
- 你头壳坏去吗? - 我是说很好喝,再来一杯啊
- Well, you could have just said so. - I just did.
- 那你用讲的就好啊 - 我刚才讲了
- No, I mean, ask nicely. - I meant no disrespect.
- 我是说用"讲"的就好 - 我也没恶意
All right. Well, no more smashing.
好吧,那么别砸杯子了
Deal?
知道吧?
You have my word.
没问题
Good.
很好
The usual, please, Izzy.
餐点照旧啊西斯
You missed all the excitement out at the crater.
你可错过陨石坑那边好玩的事了
They're saying some kind of satellite landed out in the desert.
我看过很多卫星坠毁在沙漠地的事了
Yeah, we were having a good time with it
是啊,我们本来可好好玩的
until the Feds showed up.
直到调查局来了
- Excuse me. - Did you say there was a satellite crash?
- 抱歉 - 你刚提到有"卫星坠毁"的事?
Yeah.
是啊
Oh, my God. This is going on Facebook. Smile.
天啊,帮你贴到Facebook上秀一下
What did it look like, the satellite?
请问那个卫星长得怎样?
I don't know anything about satellites, but it was heavy.
我不太懂什么卫星,但是它很重
I mean, nobody could lift it.
根本抬不动它
They said it was radioactive. I had my hands all over it.
有人说要小心辐射污染之类别的
Which way?
在哪个方位?
Fifty miles west of here.
往西方50英里处
Well, I wouldn't waste my time!
我可不想浪费时间!
Looked like the whole Army was coming when we left.
到时会来一堆军队
Dumbass!
混蛋!
Where are you going?
你在干嘛?
- Fifty miles west of here. - Why?
- 往西边50英里处走啊 - 为何?
To get what belongs to me.
去找回我的东西
Oh, so you own a satellite now?
你是说那卫星是你的啊?
It's not what they say it is.
不适他们谈论的"那个东西"
Well, whatever it is,
无论它是什么
the government seems to think it's theirs.
但政府机构似乎认为那个东西是他们的了
So, you just intend to go in there and take it?
而你就打算去到那里后,拿了就走?
Yes.
是啊
If you take me there now,
如果你带我过去
I'll tell you everything you wish to know.
我将告诉你所有你想知道的事情
- Everything? - Yes.
- 所有的? - 是的
All the answers you seek will be yours once I reclaim Mjolnir.
我将告诉你有关雷神之锤的秘密
Myeu-muh? What's Myeu-muh?
雷神之锤?,什么是雷神之锤?
Can I have a word, Jane?
能说句话吗,珍妮?
Please don't do this.
拜托别这样做啊
You saw what I saw last night.
你也看到昨晚发生的事情
This is no coincidence. We have to find out what's in that crater.
这不是巧合,我们得去解陨石坑的真相的
But I'm not talking about the crater, I'm talking about him.
但我不是指陨石坑的事,我是指"他"!
- But he's promising us the answers. - He's delusional.
- 我们答应他就好啊 - 他疯了
Listen to what he's saying.
你听他在讲什么
He's talking about Mjolnir and Thor and Bifrost.
他在说什么雷神之锤、托尔、彩虹桥
It's the stories I grew up with as a child.
不过是咱从小听过的故事罢了
I'm just going to drive him. That's it.
就载他过去而已
He's dangerous, Jane.
有危险啊,珍妮
I'm sorry, but I can't take you.
抱歉,我无法带你过去
Then this is where we say goodbye.
那我们就该在这里道别
Thank you?
谢谢?
Jane Foster,
珍妮·佛斯特
Erik Selvig,
艾瑞克
Darcy,
妲西
farewell.
后会了
All right.
好吧
Back to work.
回去办事了
That's my stuff!
嘿那是我的东西啊!
What the hell is going on here?
这里在做什么事情啊?
Ms. Foster, I'm Agent Coulson with S.H.I.E.L.D.
佛斯特小姐,我是卡申探员,来自神盾局
Is that supposed to mean something to me?
那应该是对我暗示什么吗?
- You can't do this! - Jane!
- 你不能做这些! - 简!
Jane, this is a lot more serious than you realize. Let it go.
珍妮,情况比你想像的还糟糕,放手吧
Let it go? This is my life.
放手?这是我毕生的研究啊
We're investigating a security threat.
如果有机密上的安全威胁时
We need to appropriate your records and all your atmospheric data.
您的研究资料跟纪录将会提供协助
By "appropriate," do you mean steal?
恰当地说,你们用偷窃的?
Here, this should more than compensate you
来吧,这些钱当作弥补您的
for your trouble.
一些损失吧
I can't just buy replacements at Radio Shack,
在无线电器材公司是买不到的
I made most of this equipment myself!
我那些设备是我自己做的!
Then I'm sure you can do it again.
我确定您可重新开始研究的
And I'm sure I can sue you for violating my constitutional rights!
我可确定的是大可控告你们侵犯我的宪法保障权!
I'm sorry, Ms. Foster, but we're the good guys.
抱歉,佛斯特小姐,我们是好人
So are we!
我也是啊!
I'm on the verge of understanding something extraordinary.
我正将解开一些未解的奇异现象之谜
And everything I know about this phenomenon
关于这种现象我所知道的每一件事
is either in this lab or in this book.
不是在实验室就是在书里
And you can't just take this away...
但你不可就拿走啊...
Jane! Easy! Easy. Jane...
珍妮!放松!放松,珍妮
Thank you for your cooperation.
感谢您的合作
Years of research,
多年的研究成果
gone.
没了
They even took my iPod.
连我iPod随身听也拿走了
- What about the backups? - They took our backups.
- 那备份资料呢? - 也被拿走了
They took the backups of our backups. They were extremely thorough.
连备份的备份资料也都拿走了
I just downloaded, like, 30 songs onto there.
里面装了了30首,mp3然后
Could you please stop with your iPod?
拜托别再提你的iPod好吗?
Who are these people?
这些人是谁啊?
I knew this scientist.
我认识一个科学家
The pioneer in gamma radiation.
是研究迦玛射线的先驱(指绿巨人浩克)
S.H.I.E.L.D. showed up
他曾提神盾局的事情
and he wasn't heard from again.
就下落不明了
They're not gonna do that to us. I'm gonna get everything back.
他们不能这样对待我,我要拿回所有的东西
Come on, please. Let me contact one of my colleagues.
请让我先连络我以前的一个同事
He's had some dealings with these people before.
他曾跟这些家伙接触过的
I'll e-mail him and maybe he can help.
给他先发个e-mail,也许他帮得上忙
They took your laptop, too.
他们也抢走你的电脑了
Allfather, we must speak with you urgently.
父王啊,我们得先跟您说几句话
My friends.
朋友们
Where's Odin?
奥丁父王呢?
Father has fallen into the Odinsleep.
父王正在沉睡当中
Mother fears he may never awaken again.
母王也担心他不会在醒来
We would speak with her.
我们跟女王说话
She has refused to leave my father's bedside.
女王不愿离开父王身边
You can bring your urgent matter to me.
你们大可跟我报告有何急事
Your king.
你们的"王"!
My King, we would ask that you end Thor's banishment.
吾王我希望赦免托尔的罪罚
My first command cannot be to undo the Allfather's last.
我第一个命令不能违反父王的最后一个命令
We're on the brink of war with Jotunheim.
我们正在跟"乔登海姆"开战中
Our people need a sense of continuity,
我们的百姓需要和平
in order to feel safe in these difficult times.
在此危机时刻为了需要安全感
All of us must stand together
我们都该协手同心
for the good of Asgard.
为了"阿斯嘉特"国度
Yes, of course.
那当然
- Good. Then you will wait for my word. - If I may
- 你们只等我一声令下罢了 - 恕我直言
beg the indulgence of Your Majesty to perhaps reconsider...
国王是否多需考量一下...
We're done!
就这样!
I need a horse!
我要一匹马!
We don't have horses. Just dogs, cats, birds...
我们只有猫狗鸟类别等宠物罢了...
Then give me one of those large enough to ride.
那给我一个能让我骑乘的动物
Hey, you still need a lift?
嘿,你还需要搭个便车吗?
I've never done anything like this before.
我不曾如此的乱来过
Have you ever done anything like this before?
你以前有这样做过吗?
Many times.
随时随地都会
But you're brave to do it.
但你很敢于这么做
Well, they just stole my entire life's work.
那些家伙偷走我毕生心血
I don't really have much left to lose.
我就没什么事情我不敢做的了
Yeah, but you're clever.
你挺聪明是吧
Far more clever than anyone else in this realm.
感觉你比国度里很多人聪明似的
"Realm"? "Realm"?
"国度"?"国度"?
- You think me strange. - Yeah, I do.
- 听来很奇怪 - 是啊
Good strange or bad strange?
听来是好是坏呢?
I'm not quite sure yet.
我可不确定啊
I'm sorry.
抱歉了
But who are you?
但你到底是谁啊你?
Really?
真的?
You'll see soon enough.
很快你便知道了
You promised me answers.
你答应给我答案的
What you seek, it's a bridge.
你在找所谓的"虫洞"吧
Like an Einstein-Rosen Bridge?
你是说:"爱因斯坦·罗森桥"?
More like a Rainbow Bridge.
我们称之为:彩虹桥
God, I hope you're not crazy.
真希望你没疯了
I never get used to seeing him like this.
我不忍看到他变成这样
He's put it off for so long now, that I fear...
他一直沉睡着,让我感到害怕...
How long will it last?
他还能撑多久呢?
I don't know. This time it's different. We were unprepared.
我不知道,这回状况不同,我们没做好准备
So why did he lie?
那他为何对我说谎?
He kept the truth from you so that you would never feel different.
他隐瞒真相只为了怕你感觉到与众不同
You are our son, Loki,
你是我们的儿子,洛基
and we, your family.
我们是一家人啊
We mustn't lose hope that your father will return to us.
我们不可放弃希望,希望你父王能回到我们身边
And your brother.
关于你兄弟
What hope is there for Thor?
托尔会怎样呢?
There's always a purpose to everything your father does.
那正是你父亲对托尔所要表达的用意
That's no satellite crash!
那可不是卫星坠落的景象!
They would have hauled the wreckage away,
他们应该是把残骸全拖走了
they wouldn't have built a city around it.
他们应该不会在坠落区建个城市吧
- You're going to need this. - What? Wait, why?
- 你需要这个 - 什么?等等,为何?
Now stay here.
待在原地
Once I have Mjolnir, I will return the items they've stolen from you.
一旦我成功潜入那里,我答应帮你拿回你的东西
Deal?
好吗?
No. Look what's down there.
不好,你认真看看那里
You think you're just gonna walk in, grab our stuff and walk out?
你认为你可大喇喇走进去,拿了东西就走人是吗?
No. I'm going to fly out.
不,我用"飞"的
Sir, feed from the keyhole can barely penetrate the cloud cover.
长官,有不明飞行物似乎穿过虫洞飞来
Tech's barely working as it is,
电子设备因此几乎不工作了
with all the interference that thing's giving off.
因为那个飞行物发出了干扰作用
And we've got a commercial aircraft coming right over us.
并且我们看到一架民航机正在经过领空
Southwest Airlines, flight 5434.
西南航空的5434号班机
Reroute it like all the others.
还有其他飞行物
Hold a sec.
等等
We've got something outside the fence, west side.
有其他东西正在咱的防御线边缘,在西边
Delancey, Jackson.
德兰西,这是杰克森
West side perimeter Go check it out.
请查明西方维护区状况
There it is.
到了
Delancey, Jackson. Report.
德兰西,这是杰克森,请回报
Agent down. We've got a perimeter breach.
有人员伤亡,防卫线被突破了
You've reached Dr Erik Selvig. Please leave me a message.
你拨的电话没回应,想留言给艾瑞克请说
Hi, Erik, it's me. Don't worry, I'm fine,
艾瑞克,是我,我很好
but just in case you don't hear from me in the next hour,
但是万一我一小时后没回拨给你
just come by the crater site and try and find me, okay?
我正在做你叫我别干的事,好吗?
I did exactly what you told me not to. I'm sorry.
我正在陨石坑忙点事情之类别的
So sorry. Bye.
我很抱歉再见了
Entering south tunnel!
有人硬闯通道!
- Negative, negative. - I have no comms.
- 拒绝,拒绝 - 我没看到啊
Target sighted, east tunnel!
1号通道需要支援
I need eyes up high, with a gun.
我们需要武装支援
Moving north!
他往北方跑了!
What have we got?
现况如何呢?
There's a massive electromagnetic surge
有一股大量的电磁浪涌
coming off that thing.
从那个东西出来的
Systems are barely coping.
系统快撑不住了
Barton? Talk to me.
巴顿?请说
You want me to slow him down, sir?
你要挡下他吗,长官?
Or are you sending in more guys for him to beat up?
还是你要让更多手下被挨揍呢?
I'll let you know.
我再告诉你
You're big.
好样的
Fought bigger.
我打败过比你更行的
Better call it, Coulson, 'cause I'm starting to root for this guy.
你得快下命令,卡森,这家伙越来越难搞了
Last chance, sir.
最后机会,长官
Wait. I want to see this.
等等,我想静观其变
All right, show's over. Ground units, move in.
好了,搞怪秀结束,把他抓起来吧
He committed a crime. He's in jail!
他已认罪,也入狱了!
- I can't just leave him there! - Why?
- 我不能弃他而不顾啊 - 为什么?
You didn't see what I saw!
你从没看过我所看见的!
- Look! - Look, it's Myeu-muh.
- 看! - 看,是雷神之锤
Where'd you find this?
在哪发现的?
The children's section.
童话故事里
I just wanted to show you how silly his story was.
我想向你证明他的故事是多么愚蠢
But you're the one who's always pushing me
但你是一直鞭策我
to chase down every possibility, every alternative!
要竭尽所能去发掘真相的啊!
I'm talking about science, not magic!
我是叫你研究科学,不是研究魔法!
Well, magic's just science that we don't understand yet.
但魔法是我们科学还无法验证的东西
- Arthur C. Clarke. - Who wrote science fiction.
- 亚瑟.克拉克的铭言 - 那是谁在写科幻小说呢
- A precursor to science fact! - In some cases, yeah.
- 至少有依靠一些科学根据吧! - 某些状况之下是的
Well, if there is an Einstein-Rosen Bridge,
如果"爱因斯坦·罗森桥"存在
then there's something on the other side.
那么虫洞理论存在的
And advanced beings could have crossed it!
也许可以跨越另一个宇宙!
Jane.
珍妮
A primitive culture like the Vikings might have worshipped them as deities.
像维京人那样的原始文明就会把他们当神灵一样供奉
Yes! Yes, exactly. Thank you.
是的!太对了,谢谢
You made my men,
是你伤了我们一些探员
some of the most highly trained professionals in the world,
这些都是世界上受到高度专业训练的探员
look like a bunch of minimum-wage mall cops.
变得好像淑辣般脆弱
that's hurtful.
身受痛苦啊
In my experience, it takes someone who's received similar training
依我经验判断那样的行为,肯定受过高专业的训练
to do what you did to them.
好让你对付他们
Why don't you tell me where you received your training?
为什么不告诉我你在哪里受训的?
Pakistan? Chechnya? Afghanistan?
巴基斯坦?车臣?阿富汗?
No, you strike me more as the soldier of fortune type.
感觉你又很像佣兵
Where was it? South Africa?
在南非服役过吗?
Certain groups pay very well for a good mercenary like you.
很多财团会付大笔佣金雇请你这种佣兵的
Who are you?
你是谁呢?
One way or another, we find out what we need to know.
无论如何,我们会查出我们想知道的事
We're good at that.
这我们很在行的
Don't go anywhere.
别乱跑啊你
Loki! What are you doing here?
洛基!你来这做什么?
I had to see you.
我得见你
What's happened?
怎么了?
Tell me. Is it Jotunheim?
跟"神之国度"的事有关吗?
Let me explain to Father.
让我跟父王解释
Father is dead.
父王死了
What?
什么?
Your banishment,
你的放逐
the threat of a new war,
正威胁着一场战争
it was too much for him to bear.
但风险太大了
You mustn't blame yourself.
这你得自责
I know that you loved him.
我知道你爱父王
I tried to tell him so, but he wouldn't listen.
我试着跟父王解释,他也不听
It was so cruel to put the hammer within your reach,
夺走你能使用雷神之槌的法力是很残酷
knowing that you could never lift it.
既使知道你已不能举起它
The burden of the throne has fallen to me now.
如今国王的重担落在我头上了
Can I come home?
我能回家了吗?
The truce with Jotunheim is conditional upon your exile.
神之国度的停战协议,包括了放逐你
Yes, but couldn't we find a way...
是的,但没有其它方法...
And Mother has forbidden your return.
母后也同意你的禁令
This is goodbye, Brother.
该说再见了,兄弟
I'm so sorry.
我深表遗憾
No.
不
I am sorry.
是我该对不起
Thank you for coming here.
感谢你的来访
Farewell.
永别了
Goodbye.
再见了
Good bye?
再见?
I just got back.
我才刚进来
Sir?
长官
He's got a visitor.
有人来访
His name is Donald Blake?
他叫唐纳·布雷克?
Dr. Donald Blake.
唐纳·布雷克博士
You have dangerous coworkers, Dr. Selvig.
你有个危险的同事,席维克博士
He was distraught when he found out that you've taken all our research.
他发狂了,当他看到你们毁掉了他所有的研究成果
That was years of his life, gone!
那是他多年的心血,没了!
You can understand how a man could go off like that.
你能理解一个男人是怎么做到那样的
A big, faceless organization like yours
一个像你们这样的庞大隐秘的组织
coming in with their jackbooted thugs and...
带着穿长统靴的暴徒闯进来,并且...
That's how he put it.
所以他会有这样的行为
That still doesn't explain
这也不足以说明
how he managed to tear through our security.
他是如何躲过卫兵的
Steroids! He's a bit of a fitness nut.
服用类胆固醇,他是个健身狂
Sir?
长官?
It says here that he's an M.D.
资料上显示他是"医学教授"
Well, he is! Or he was.
嗯,是啊!或者以前是
He switched careers and became a physicist.
他转行当了科学家了物理领域
A brilliant physicist.
好个聪明的物理学家
He's a wonderful man. He's a man in pain.
他是个好人,虽深受痛苦
Oh, Donny, Donny, Donny!
唐尼,唐尼啊!
There you are. You're gonna be all right. I'm taking you home now.
你在这儿,你会没事的,我带你回家去
Dr. Selvig!
席维克博士
Just keep him away from the bars.
别让他喝酒了
I will!
没问题!
- Where are we going? - To get a drink.
- 我们要去哪? - 喝一杯吧
Follow them.
追踪他们
You know, I had it all backwards.
我知道我做错了
I had it all wrong.
全部都做错了
It's not a bad thing finding out that you don't have all the answers.
你不必全部的问题都知道答案,也是不赖
You start asking the right questions.
有时只要问对问题就好了
For the first time in my life,
有生以来第一次
I have no idea what I'm supposed to do.
我不知道自己要干嘛
Anyone who's ever going to find his way in this world
每个人都能找到出路的
has to start by admitting he doesn't know where the hell he is.
只是还不知道出路在哪罢了
Thank you for what you've done.
感谢你的帮忙
No, don't thank me. I only did it for Jane.
不,别谢我,我是帮忙珍妮而做的
Her father and I taught at university together.
他父亲跟我曾一起在大学教书
He was a good man.
他是好人
He never listened.
但我从没把话听进去
Neither did I.
我也一样
My father was trying to teach me something,
我父亲总想教会我一些事
but I was too stupid to see it.
是我愚蠢到无法理解他想说的
I don't know if you're delusional
我不知道你是在妄想
or if you're pulling some kind of con,
还是你想对着干
I don't care.
我也不在乎
I just care about her.
我只在乎她
I've seen the way she looks at you.
我了解她看着你的眼神
I swear to you, I mean her no harm.
我向你发誓,我不会伤害她
Good.
很好
In that case, I'll buy you another round,
我再请你多喝一杯吧
and you leave town tonight.
你今晚离开这城镇吧
Two boilermakers.
来两杯深水炸弹
Kill him.
杀了他
After all I've done for you?
在我为你做这么多事后?
So you're the one who showed us the way into Asgard.
原来就是你指引我们侵入"阿斯嘉特"的人
That was just a bit of fun, really.
我觉得挺好玩罢了
To ruin my brother's big day.
故意搞乱我大哥加冕的好日子
And to protect the realm from his idiotic rule for a while longer.
还顺便保护我们国度免于被他的愚蠢所害
I will hear you.
我听说了
I will conceal you and a handful of your soldiers,
我将把你跟你的战士给隐藏得很好
lead you into Odin's chambers, and you can slay him where he lies.
领你到奥丁父王的寝宫,然后你可以杀了他
Why not kill him yourself?
你何不自己动手杀了他?
I suspect that the Asgardians would not take kindly
我认为晚辈还是别
to a king who had murdered his predecessor.
杀害前辈比较仁慈些
Once Odin is dead, I will return the Casket to you
一旦奥丁父王一死,我就归还你的法力之源
and you can return Jotunheim to all its...
而你将可以重返"乔登海姆"还原你昔日的...
Glory.
荣耀
Accept.
我接受
What troubles you, Gatekeeper?
有何问题吗,守护者?
I turned my gaze upon you in Jotunheim,
我把彩虹之门朝向"乔登海姆"
but could neither see you nor hear you.
却只能看见你但听不见你的声音
You were shrouded from me,
你想隐瞒我
like the Frost Giants that entered this realm.
就像寒冰巨人曾侵入这里一般
Perhaps your senses have weakened after your many years of service.
也许在你任职这么久之后你的感官退化了
Or perhaps someone has found a way
也可能是有发现什么方法
to hide that which he does not wish me to see.
好隐藏自己不被人发现似的
You have great power, Heimdall.
你有很好的神力,海姆达尔
Did Odin ever fear you?
奥丁父王曾畏惧过你吗?
- No. - And why is that?
- 没有 - 为何?
Because he is my king and I am sworn to obey him.
因为他是我的国王,我宣示过忠诚!
He was your king and you're sworn to obey me now.
如果是国王,你也会对我宣誓效忠
Yes?
是吧?
Yes.
是的
Then you will open the Bifrost to no one
那就别再开启彩虹桥
until I have repaired the damage that my brother has done.
在我弥补好我老哥所做的错事之前
Oh, my God. Is he okay?
天啊,还好吧?
He's fine. Not injured at all.
他很好,一点也没受伤
I'm sorry, my friend.
抱歉,伙计
- What happened? - We drank, we fought,
- 怎么了? - 我们大醉,又干架
he made his ancestors proud.
让观众大呼过瘾
Put him on the bed.
把他放床上
I still don't think you're the God of Thunder.
我还是不相信你是雷神
But you ought to be.
但你应该当雷神
Are these your chambers?
这是您住的地方?
It's more of a temporary living situation.
这是暂住的小窝而已
I'm sorry. I don't usually have guests.
真抱歉很少有访客来
Actually, I never have guests.
事实上没访客来过啦
That's not the right place for it.
我一个人惯了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Can we go outside?
到外面坐坐吧?
Yes, of course.
好的,当然
I come up here sometimes when I can't sleep
我有时睡不着会跑来这而
or I'm trying to reconcile particle data,
或者整理一下我的思绪
or when Darcy's driving me crazy.
或者妲西搞得我很烦时
I come up here a lot, actually, now that I think about it.
想想我还真常跑来这儿
I'm really glad you're safe.
很高兴你没事
You've been very kind to me,
你们对我很好
and I've been far less grateful than you deserve.
我可能不值得如此相待
Well, I hit you with my car a couple times,
你被我的车撞两次了
so I think that kind of evens things out.
我们算扯平了
Perhaps I had it coming.
也许是吧
Oh, my God!
天啊!
I don't believe it!
真不敢相信!
It was all I could get back. I'm sorry it's not as much as I promised.
我顺手偷回的,抱歉我没拿回所有东西
No, no, this is great! This is...
不,不,很够了!这是...
I don't have to start from scratch now.
我不用重新开始画那些素描图了
Thank you.
谢谢
What's wrong?
怎么了?
S.H.l.E.L.D.
神盾局的人
Whatever they are,
无论如何
they're gonna do everything in their power
他们大可以运用公权力
to make sure this research never sees the light of day.
确保这些研究再也见不到日光
No, Jane.
不,珍妮
Listen to me. You must not give up.
听我说,你不要放弃
- You must finish what you've started. - Why?
- 你必须要在开始就结束 - 为何?
Because you're right.
因为你作对的事情
Here, look.
你看
Your ancestors called it magic, and you call it science.
你们先人曾叫它魔法,而你称它为科学
Well, I come from a place where they're one and the same thing.
我却来自你们所宣称的这一切事物
What is that?
那是什么?
My father explained it to me like this,
我父王是这样跟我解释的
that your world
你们的世界
is one of the Nine Realms of the Cosmos,
是这九大国度的其中一个
linked to each other by the branches of Yggdrasil,
你们彼此互相牵连着
the Worlds Tree.
称之世界之树
Now you see it every day without realizing.
你每天都在看却不了解含意
The images glimpsed through... What did you call it?
图像透过这个...你管这个叫什么?
This Hooble Telescope.
叫哈勃望远镜
- Hubble. - Hubble Telescope.
- 哈伯 - 抱歉哈伯望远镜
Tell me more.
多说一点
So, the Nine Realms.
这里的九大国度
Now, there is Midgard, which is Earth.
这是米德加得,就是地球
This is Alfheim.
接着是爱菲海姆
Vanaheim. Jotunheim.
安纳海姆,卓顿海姆
And Asgard.
阿斯加德
And that's where I come from.
我正来自那个地方
Thank you, Jane.
谢谢,珍妮
Our dearest friend banished, Loki on the throne,
我们的好友被放逐,而洛基正要被加冕
Asgard on the brink of war, yet you've managed to consume
"阿斯嘉特"正面临战争边缘,而你还在这里大吃大喝
four wild boar, six pheasant, a side of beef,
四头野猪肉,六只野鸡,半只牛肉
and two casks of ale. Shame on you. Don't you care?
吃饭而已,你们真是丢脸,你们不在乎吗?
Do not mistake my appetite for apathy!
别在我面前胡言乱语,坏了我胃口!
Stop it, both of you!
停!住手!
Stop.
住手
- We all know what we have to do. - We must go.
- 我们都知道该怎么做 - 我们该出发了
We must find Thor.
一定要找到托尔
It's treason.
那是背叛
To hell with treason, it's suicide.
才不是背叛,是自杀
Thor would do the same for us.
托尔也会为我们这样做的
Now shush.
闭嘴
Heimdall might be watching.
海姆达尔,还在看守着
Heimdall demands your presence.
海姆达尔召见各位
We're doomed.
完蛋了
You would defy the commands of Loki, our king,
你们打算违背"我们国王"洛基的命令
break every oath you have taken as warriors,
你们甘愿打破战士的誓言
and commit treason to bring Thor back?
甚至身负背叛之罪只为了救回托尔?
- Yes. - Good.
- 是的 - 好极了
So you'll help us?
你要帮忙?
I am bound by honor to our king.
我肩负着国王的光荣
I cannot open the bridge to you.
我将开启彩虹之门
Complicated fellow, isn't he?
越搞越复杂了,是吗?
Now what do we do?
接下来呢?
Look!
看!
- What the hell was that? - I don't know, sir.
- 那是怎一回事啊? - 不知道啊,长官
We got massive energy readings out of nowhere
一时有道强大的能源指数
and then they just disappeared. Fifteen miles due northwest.
但随即又消失了,在西北方15英里处
Let's go take a look.
快去看看
Thank you.
谢谢
- Thank you. - You're very welcome.
- 谢谢 - 不用客气
Base to Team 2, we've got activity outside the town.
第2队,我们持续监控城镇边缘
Stay on your target.
盯住目标
Ensure my brother does not return.
确保我弟兄永不能回来
Destroy everything.
毁灭一切
Mom?
妈咪?
Is there a Renaissance Fair in town?
这是在做什么文艺复兴类的展览是吧?
Call it in.
回报给总部
Yeah.
是的
Base, we've got Xena, Jackie Chan and Robin Hood.
发现了西嘉公主、成龙、罗宾汉之类别的人
It's a beautiful theory, Jane.
那是很好的臆测,珍妮
But you won't be able to convince the scientific community of any of it.
但这无法让你进入科学协会里
Not without hard evidence.
因没有证据啊
Found you!
找到你啦!
My friends!
我的好友!
This is good! This is good.
真是棒啊!真是棒啊
I don't believe it.
真不敢相信
Oh, excuse me. Lady Sif and the Warriors Three.
抱歉,希芙女士和战士三人组
My friends,
朋友们
I've never been happier to see anyone.
见到你们真是荣幸啊
But you should not have come.
但你们不该来的
We're here to take you home.
我们来带你回家的
You know I can't go home.
你知道我回不了家了
My father
我父王
is dead because of me.
是因我而死
And I must remain in exile.
我本该被放逐
Thor,
托尔
your father still lives.
你的父王还活着
Tell me, Loki, how did you get the Jotuns into Asgarol?
告诉我,洛基,你是怎放行寒冰巨人侵入的?
You think the Bifrost is the only way in and out of this realm?
你以为彩虹桥是唯一可以传送到各国度的方法吗?
There are secret paths between the worlds
但有一条秘密的通道
to which even you, with all your gifts, are blind.
是你的能力无法去驾驭的,你被蒙蔽了
But I have need of them no longer, now that I am king.
但我不需要了,我是国王了
And I say, for your act of treason,
基于你违抗命令
you are relieved of your duties as Gatekeeper,
我解除你的看门人职务
and no longer citizen of Asgard.
且你不属于神之国度的一员了
Then I need no longer obey you.
那我就不必效忠你了
Get somebody from Linguistics down here.
找个古文学家来
Was somebody else coming?
还有人要来吗?
Is that one of StarK's?
是史塔克的钢铁人吗?
I don't know. The guy never tells me anything.
不知道,史塔克什么都不会说
Hello.
你好
You are using unregistered weapons technology.
你在未经许可领域使用武器
Identify yourself
报上名来
Here we go.
果然是
Incoming!
快闪开!
Jane, you have to leave.
珍妮,你快走
- What are you gonna do? - I'm staying here.
- 但你怎么办? - 我留下
Thor's going to fight with us!
托尔将与我们并肩作战!
My friends,
朋友们
I'm just a man. I'll only be in the way, or worse, get one of you killed.
我已是凡人了,留下来奋战的话,可能会有人丧命的
But I can help get these people to safety.
但可以说明人们尽量逃到安全之处
Well, if you're staying, then so am I.
若你留下,我也是
- We'll need some time. - You'll have it!
- 争取点时间 - 可以的!
Okay, move it, people!
快点快跑啊各位!
Everybody out! Use the back door.
通通出去!从安全门逃出去
Go, hurry! You can eat later.
快点快逃啊!你以后再吃
Keep it distracted.
让它分心一点
For Asgard!
为国度而战
Fall back!
撤退!
Go. Now. Run!
快跑!
Sif. Sif, you've done all you can.
希芙,希芙,听着你们尽力了
No. I will die a warrior's death.
不,我将死得像个战士般
Stories will be told of this day.
让后代可以传颂着
Live, and tell those stories yourself.
不如你活着自己来讲这经历
Now go.
快走
You must return to Asgard. You have to stop Loki.
你们得回去"阿斯嘉特"并阻止洛基
What about you?
那你呢?
Do not worry, my friends. I have a plan.
别担心我,朋友们,我自有计划
Come on.
快点
We need to fall back. Come on.
快撤退,快点
Come on.
快点
Wait!
等等!
What's he doing?
他在做什么?
Brother, whatever I have done to wrong you,
兄弟,若我曾经做了什么对不起你的
whatever I have done to lead you to do this,
无论我做了什么让你得这样对待我
I am truly sorry.
我诚恳道歉
But these people are innocent.
但请别残害无辜
Taking their lives will gain you nothing.
若你害死他们毫无益处
So take mine
杀了我
and end this.
结束这些
No.
不
It's over.
都结束了
No. it's not over.
不,还没结束
I mean, you're safe.
至少你安全了
We're safe.
是的
It's over.
那就是结束了
No.
不
- We're spiking. - Levels increase!
- 正在失效 - 水平增加了!
Whosoever holds this hammer,
无论是谁掌握了雷神之鎚
if he be worthy,
只要他够资格
shall possess the power of Thor.
就能拥有雷神之力
Jane!
珍妮!
- No. No. No! - Come!
- 不!不!不! - 走吧!
Oh. My. God.
我的天啊
So, is this how you normally look?
还原正常了?
More or less.
差不多吧
It's a good look.
看来挺帅的
We must go to the Bifrost site. I would have words with my brother.
我们得赶到彩虹桥去,好让我跟我弟讲讲话
Excuse me!
抱歉!
Donald?
唐那先生
I don't think you've been completely honest with me.
你好像没对我说实话喔
Know this, Son of Coul.
非无敬意
You and I, we fight for the same cause, the protection of this world.
你和我,都是为了同一信念而战:保卫世界
From this day forward, you can count me as your ally
而今日是你跟同事可表现之时
if you return the items you have taken from Jane.
但先请把珍妮的所有研究资料还她
- Stolen. - Borrowed.
- 被偷的 - 借来的
Of course, you can have your equipment back.
你可以领回所有的器材
You're gonna need it to continue your research.
好让你继续你的研究
Would you like to see the bridge we spoke of?
你想看看我讲的彩虹桥吗?
Sure.
那当然
Wait, I need to debrief you!
等等,我要听你汇报!
Welcome to Asgard.
欢迎来到"阿斯嘉特"
Heimdall, open the Bifrost.
海姆达尔,开启彩虹桥
Heimdall?
海姆达尔?
Heimdall!
海姆达尔!
He doesn't answer.
没人回应
Then we are stranded.
他被控制住了
Heimdall! If you can hear me, we need you now!
海姆达尔!若你听到了,我们需要你协助!
Heimdall! We need you now!
海姆达尔,我们需要你协助!
Heimdall!
海姆达尔!
I must go back to Asgard, but I give you my word,
我必须赶回我们需要你协助,但我想你保证
I will return for you.
我会为你回来的
Deal?
一言为定?
Deal.
一言为定
Get him to the healing room!
快把伤者送到疗伤室!
Leave my brother to me.
把我哥哥留给我
It's Said
据说
you can still hear and see what transpires around you.
你竟然还能听得见看得见
I hope it's true,
我希望是真的
so that you may know
亲自体验到
your death came at the hand of Laufey.
是我劳菲杀了你
And your death came by the son of Odin.
但你却是被奥丁之子给杀了
Loki!
洛基!
You saved him!
你救了他!
I swear to you, Mother,
我向你发誓,母后
that they will pay for what they've done today.
他们将为今天所做的付出代价
Loki.
洛基
Thor!
托尔!
I knew you'd return to us.
我就知道你会回来
Why don't you tell her
你怎不解释为何
how you sent the Destroyer to kill our friends, to kill me?
你派出毁灭者想杀了我跟我的朋友?
What?
什么?
Why, it must have been enforcing Father's last command.
我不过接任"先父"的指挥权罢了
You're a talented liar, Brother. Always have been.
你真是老练的说谎家,兄弟,一直都是
It's good to have you back.
很高兴你回得来
Now if you'll excuse me, I have to destroy Jotunheim.
但很抱歉,我得先去毁灭:"乔登海姆"
You can't stop it.
你看着
The Bifrost will build until it rips Jotunheim apart.
看我怎么将"乔登海姆"给彻底毁灭
Jane?
珍妮?
Why have you done this?
你为何要这样做?
To prove to Father that I am the worthy son.
我只想向父王证明我才是够格的
When he wakes, I will have saved his life.
当他醒来后,会知道是我救了他
I will have destroyed that race of monsters.
是我平定了这些怪兽的作乱
And I will be true heir to the throne!
我才够格戴上皇冠!
You can't kill an entire race!
你也不能消灭个种族的!
Why not?
为何不?
And what is this newfound love for the Frost Giants?
你又何时开始同情起寒冰巨人一族了呢?
You could have killed them all with your bare hands.
你大可轻而易举的灭族啊
- I've changed. - So have I.
- 我改变心意了 - 我也是
Now fight me.
跟我决斗吧
I never wanted the throne!
我不是只要皇冠!
I only ever wanted to be your equal.
我只想跟你平起平坐
I will not fight you, Brother!
我不想跟你决斗的,兄弟!
I'm not your brother.
我不是你兄弟
I never was.
从来不是亲兄弟
Loki, this is madness.
洛基,这太疯狂了
Is it madness?
这疯狂吗?
Is it?
是吗?
Come on. What happened to you on Earth that turned you so soft?
我不知何原因让你去了地球变得如此脆弱?
Don't tell me it was that woman.
但请别说是为了一个女人
It was!
果然是!
Well, maybe, when we're finished here, I'll pay her a visit myself!
也许等我俩忙完这里后,我去给她登门拜访!
Thor!
托尔!
Brother, please.
兄弟,拜托了
Enough!
够了!
Look at you,
看看你自己
the Mighty Thor,
伟大的雷神托尔
with all your strength,
你有如此的神力
and what good does it do you now, huh?
你现在又能怎样呢?
Do you hear me, Brother? There's nothing you can do!
你听见了吗,兄弟?你无能为力的!
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
If you destroy the bridge, you'll never see her again!
你毁了彩虹之桥,就再也没机会见到她了!
Forgive me, Jane.
原谅我,珍妮
I could have done it, Father!
我能成功的,父王!
I could have done it!
我能成功的!
For you!
为你!
For all of us!
为了我们!
NO, Loki.
不,洛基
Loki, no.
洛基,不
No!
不!
No.
不
it's gone.
他消失了
And then, with a mighty bellow,
然后,随着一声强大的怒吼
I flew into the giant metal creature and laid him low!
我飞进了那个巨大的金属生物内并放倒了它!
Is that another way of saying you fell on your huge ass?
是不是还有一种说法,你摔了个屁股朝天?
As a matter of fact, falling was a tactic lulling the Destroyer...
事实上,下落是阻止破坏行动的一种策略...
My Queen, I'm so sorry for your loss.
母后,很遗憾您的损失
How is he?
他还好吗?
He mourns for his brother.
他还在为兄弟默哀
And...
并且...
He misses hen
他还想着"她"
The mortal.
那个凡人的
You'll be a wise king.
你将是位睿智的君王
There will never be a wiser king than you.
永不再有像你一般睿智的君王了
Or a better father.
或是一位好父亲
I have much to learn.
我还好多要学习
I know that now.
我现在懂了
Someday, perhaps,
终有一天,有可能
I shall make you proud.
我会让您以我为傲的
You've already made me proud.
我已经以你为傲了
So Earth is lost to us.
跟地球失去联系了
No.
不
There is always hope.
总是会有办法的
Can you see her?
你看得出来喔?
Yes.
那当然
I have the particle detectors!
我有粒子探测器!
Darcy, do you have the S.H.I.E.L.D. satellite codes?
妲西,找到神盾计划的通行密码了吗?
Yeah. Have you seen my taser?
快找到了,等等我一下
How is she?
她还好吗?
In the car. Come on, Jane!
快上车啊,珍妮!
She searches for you.
珍妮还在努力想找到你
《雷神》
Dr. Selvig.
席维克博士
So you're the man behind all this?
你就是幕后首脑?
It's quite a labyrinth.
真是个迷宫啊
I was thinking they're taking me down here to kill me.
我以为你叫我来是要杀我的
I've been hearing about the New Mexico situation.
新墨西哥州的事件我听说了
Your work has impressed a lot of people who are much smarter than I am.
你的工作留下了深刻印象,比我的人聪明
I have a lot to work with.
我做了很多的工作
The Foster Theory. A gateway to another dimension.
福斯特理论,进入另一纬度的通道
It's unprecedented.
没有研究先例
Isn't it?
不是吗?
Legend tells us one thing, history, another.
一个传说告诉我们,另一个历史也告诉我们
But every now and then, we find something that belongs to both.
但不时,我们发现是一样的东西
What is it?
是什么?
Power, Doctor.
无限能量
If we can figure out how to tap it,
如果我们已经发现到了使用方法
Well, I guess that's worth a look.
就试试看吧
那就试试看吧